<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infinity Doors</title>
    <link>capm96.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Infinity Doors</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 20:12:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="capm96.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Money Boats</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/etfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 20:12:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/etfs/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: None of this should be considered as financial advice. Please do your own research before investing anything. There is no easy way to make money. The goal here is to introduce one of the thousands of ways one might invest their money, and why it can be a good idea for some people.
Think back about everything we forgot from our educational years… Why was so much time spent memorizing what a covalent bond is, instead of how to deal with the inevitable stresses of life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and Infinity</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/blackholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 18:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/blackholes/</guid>
      <description>Out there in the dark sky lies a gentle monster that would seem fictional if it were not all too real. But perhaps monster is too harsh a word, for it means no harm. Its only quarrel is with reality itself, in an attempt to push the fabric of everything to the limit.
There are things in the world that are beyond perplexing &amp;ndash; spiritual almost. Things that when thought about carefully will take one to a place of genuine awe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Need To Look Away</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/astrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 18:34:32 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/astrology/</guid>
      <description>When I was little, my mother would tell me &amp;ldquo;eat your vegetables!&amp;rdquo; all the time. Most of the time I did not want to eat the vegetables. But she would tell me &amp;ldquo;it is for your own good&amp;rdquo;, and I believed her. I believed her.
What did I know? I had no idea about the chemical effects of eating good food. I could not explain how this affected my health, but I trusted my mom, so I complied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parece mas não é</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/parece/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 20:00:41 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/parece/</guid>
      <description>When I was a kid, my mom gave me a very special book called Parece mas não é.
In Portuguese, “Parece mas não é” translates to something along the lines of “Looks like it, but it is not it ”, as in “Looks like a duck, but it is not a duck” or “Looks like a house, but it is not a house.”
The book consists of cartoonish drawings. In fact, there are almost no words in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days That Change Everything</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 17:58:03 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/days/</guid>
      <description>At this point in your life, you probably have wondered several times about how something might have turned out had certain events happened differently.
“What if I had done this?” or “What if I had not done that?”
These “what if” questions seem to be a ghost of our rationality, embedded within every human given our unique capacity to think about the past, the present, and the future. Seamlessly traveling through time in our minds can be a powerful but daunting ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Light That Guides You Home</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 22:07:43 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/gravity/</guid>
      <description>If you were asked to explain the most implausible fact you know, but which is also true without a doubt, what would it be?
I am hard pressed to find a single answer. However, one that comes to mind is that space and time are malleable components of the universe, changing under certain circumstances, and rendering extraordinary events such as the bending of time possible.
Physics is an inherently abstract subject most of the times, but what I mentioned is proven repeatedly here on Earth every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignorance, Trust, and Gratitude</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:21:56 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/ignorance/</guid>
      <description>Ignorance One of the great things about Astronomy is its unparalleled ability to create a sense of awe and humility. It is quite an astonishing effect. All it takes is looking up at the night sky and observing a glitch in our mind unfold. But before we do this, there are a few things to keep in mind. The first is to know what a light-year is.
Confusingly, a light-year is not a measure of time, but a measure of distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Beauty of (Mathematical) Irrationality</title>
      <link>capm96.github.io/post/hidden-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 16:15:04 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>capm96.github.io/post/hidden-beauty/</guid>
      <description>The words which you are reading now have no objective truth behind them. How could they? We invented them. Every single language on Earth is a human invention, designed to facilitate communication and ultimately enable us to work together cohesively. It is in fact the greatest human invention, since it is the one which all others are built upon.
However, despite its unparalleled utility, languages are only useful for communicating with other humans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
